[Music]
hello and welcome to Harry Potter and
the methods of rationality the podcast
this is a project to bring the methods
of rationality fanfiction into audio
format the original text can be found at
fanfiction.net or by googling harry
potter and the methods of rationality
and there is also a link included in
this files description I'm not a voice
actor but I'll do what I can to make it
apparent when there is dialogue
switching between two characters and
without further ado Harry Potter and the
methods of rationality written by
eliezer yudkowsky read by Yosh Brodsky
based on the works of JK Rowling chapter
one a day of very low probability
beneath the moonlight glints a tiny
fragment of silver a fraction of a line
black robes falling blood spills out in
leaders and someone screams a word every
inch of wall space is covered by a
bookcase each bookcase has six shelves
going almost to the ceiling
some bookshelves are stacked to the brim
with hardcover books science mathematics
history and everything else other shells
have two layers of paperback science
fiction with the back layer of books
propped up on old tissue boxes or
two-by-fours so that you can see the
back layer of books above the books in
front and it still isn't enough books
are overflowing onto the tables and the
sofas and making little heaps under the
windows this is the living room of the
house occupied by the eminent professor
Michael Varys Evans and his wife mrs.
petunia Evans Varys and their adopted
son Harry James Potter Evans Varys there
is a letter lying on the living room
table and an unstamped envelope of
yellowish parchment addressed to miss
sir H Potter in emerald green Inc the
professor and his wife are speaking
sharply at each other but they are not
shouting
the professor considers shouting to be
uncivilized you're joking
Michael said to petunia his tone
indicated that he was very much afraid
that she was serious my sister was a
witch petunia repeated she looked
frightened but stood her ground her
husband was a wizard this is absurd they
were at our wedding they visited for
Christmas I told them you weren't to
know but it's true I've seen things
the professor rolled his eyes dear I
understand that you're not familiar with
The Skeptical literature
you may not realize how easy it is for a
trained magician to fake the seemingly
impossible remember how I taught Harry
to bend spoons if it seemed like they
could always guess what you were
thinking that's called cold reading it
wasn't bending spoons what was it then
petunia bit her lip I can't just tell
you you'll think I'm she swallowed
listen Michael I wasn't always like this
she gestured at herself as though to
indicate her life form Lily did this
because I because I begged her for years
I begged her Lily had always been
prettier than me and I didn't mean to
her because of that and then she got
magic can you imagine how I felt and I
begged her to use some of that magic on
me so I could be pretty too even if I
couldn't have her magic at least I could
be pretty tears were gathering in
between his eyes and Lily would tell me
no and make up the most ridiculous
excuses like the world would end if she
were nice to her sister or a centaur
told her not to the most ridiculous
things and I hated her for it
and when I had just graduated from
university I was going out with this boy
Vernon Dursley and he was fat and he was
the only boy who would talk to me and he
said he wanted children and that his
first son would be named Dudley and I
thought to myself what kind of a parent
names their child Dudley Dursley it was
like I saw my whole
future stretching out in front of me and
I couldn't stand it I wrote to my sister
and I told her that if she didn't help
me I'd rather just petunia stalked
anyway she gave in she told me it was
dangerous and I said I didn't care
anymore
and I drank this potion that I was sick
for weeks but when I got better my skin
cleared up and I finally filled out it I
was beautiful people were nice to me and
after that I couldn't hate my sister
anymore especially when I learned what
her magic brought her in the end darling
you got sick you gained some weight
while resting in bed and your skin
cleared up on its own or being sick made
you change your diet she was a witch I
saw it petunia the annoyance was
creeping into his voice you know that
can't be true do I really have to
explain why petunia wrung her hands she
seemed to be on the verge of tears my
love I know I can't win arguments with
you but please you have to trust me on
this dad mum the two of them stopped and
looked at Harry as though they'd
forgotten there was a third person in
the room Harry took a deep breath mum
your parents didn't have magic did they
no petunia said looking puzzled then no
one in your family knew about magic when
Lily got her letter how did they get
convinced ah they didn't just send a
letter they send a professor from
Hogwarts he petunias eyes flicked to
Michel he showed us some magic then you
don't have to fight over this Harry said
firmly hoping against hope that this
time just this once
they would listen to him if it's true we
can just get a Hogwarts professor here
and see the magic for ourselves and dad
will admit that it's true and if not
then mum will admit that it's false
that's what the experimental method is
for so that we don't have to resolve
things just by arguing the professor
turned and looked down at him dismissive
as usual
oh come now Harry really magic
I thought you'd know better than to take
this seriously son even if you're only
ten
magic is just about the most
unscientific thing there is
Harry's mouth twisted bitterly he was
treated well probably better than most
genetic fathers treated their own
children Harry had been sent to the best
elementary schools and when that didn't
work out he was provided with tutors
from the endless labor pool of starving
students always Harry had been
encouraged to study whatever caught his
attention but all the books that caught
his fancy sponsored in whatever math or
science competitions he entered he was
given anything reasonable that he wanted
except maybe the slightest shred of
respect a tenured professor who taught
biochemistry at Oxford could hardly be
expected to listen to the advice of a
little boy you would listen to show
interest of course that's what a good
parent would do and so if you conceived
of yourself as a good parent you would
do it but take a ten-year-old seriously
hardly sometimes Harry wanted to scream
at his father mum
Harry said if you want to win this
argument with dad look in chapter 2 of
the first book of the Fineman lectures
on physics there's a quote there about
how philosophers say a great deal about
what science absolutely requires and
it's all wrong because the only rule in
science is that the final arbiter is
observation that you have to look at the
world and report what you see um I can't
think offhand of where to find something
about how it's an ideal of science to
settle things by experiment instead of
arguments his mother looked down at him
and smiled Thank You Harry but her head
rose back up to stare at her husband I
don't want to win an argument with your
father I want my husband to to listen to
the wife who loves him and trust her
just this once
Harry closed his eyes briefly hopeless
both of his parents were just hopeless
now his parents were getting into one of
those arguments again one were his
mother tried to make his father feel
guilty and his father tried to make his
mother feel stupid
I'm going to my room Harry announced his
voice trembled a little please try not
to fight too much about this mum dad
will know soon enough how it comes out
right
of course Harry said his father and his
mother gave him a reassuring kiss and
they went on fighting while Harry
climbed the stairs to his bedroom
he shut the door behind him and tried to
think the funny thing was he ought to
have agreed with dad no one had ever
seen any evidence of magic and according
to mum there was a whole magical world
out there
how could anyone keep something like
that a secret more magic that seemed
like a rather suspicious sort of excuse
it ought to have been an open-and-shut
case for Mom joking lying or being
insane in ascending order of awfulness
if mum had sent the letter herself that
would explain how it arrived at the
letterbox without a stamp a little
insanity was far far less improbable
than the universe really working like
that except that some part of Harry was
utterly convinced that magic was real
and had been since the instant he saw
the putative letter from the Hogwarts
School of Witchcraft and Wizardry
Harry rubbed his forehead grimacing
don't believe everything you think one
of his books had said but this bizarre
certainty
Harry was finding himself just expecting
that yes a hog which professor would
show up and wave a wand and magic would
come out the strange certainty was
making no effort to guard itself against
falsification wasn't making excuses in
advance for why there wouldn't be a
professor or the professor would only be
able to bend spoons where do you come
from strange little prediction Harry
directed the thought at his brain why do
I believe what I believe
usually Harry was pretty good at
answering that question but in this
particular case he had no clue what his
brain was thinking Harry gave a mental
shrug to himself a flat metal plate on a
door affords pushing and a handle on a
door of forts pulling and the thing to
do with the testable hypothesis is to go
test it he took a piece of lined paper
from his dad
and started writing dear deputy
headmistress Harry paused reflecting
then discarded the paper for another
tapping another millimeter of graphite
from his mechanical pencil this called
for careful calligraphy dear deputy
headmistress Minerva McGonagall or
whomsoever it may concern I recently
received your letter of acceptance at
Hogwarts addressed to mr. H Potter you
may not be aware that my genetic parents
James Potter and Lily Potter formerly
Lily Evans are dead I was adopted by
Lily's sister petunia Evans Varys and
her husband Michael Varys Evans I am
extremely interested in attending
Hogwarts conditional on such a place
actually existing only my mother petunia
says she knows about magic and she can't
use it herself
my father is highly skeptical I myself
am uncertain I also don't know where to
obtain any of the books or equipment
listed in your acceptance letter mother
mentioned that you sent a Hogwarts
representative to Lily Potter
then Lily Evans in order to demonstrate
to her family that magic was real and I
presume help Lily obtain her school
materials if you could do this for my
own family it would be extremely helpful
sincerely Harry James Potter Evans Faris
Harry added their current address and
then folded up the letter and put it in
an envelope which she addressed to
Hogwarts further consideration led him
to obtain a candle and drip wax onto the
flap of the envelope into which using a
penknife stip he impressed the initials
HJ p e V if he was going to descend into
this madness he was going to do it with
style then he opened his door and went
back downstairs
his father was sitting in the living
room and reading a book of higher math
to show how smart he was and his mother
was in the kitchen preparing one of his
father's favorite dishes to show how
loving she was it didn't look like they
were talking to one another at all as
scary as arguments could be not arguing
was somehow much worse
mum Harry said into the unnerving
silence I'm going to test the hypothesis
according to your theory how do I send
an owl to Hogwarts his mother turned
from the kitchen
to stare at him looking shocked I I
don't know I think you just have to own
a magic owl that should have sounded
highly suspicious oh so there's no way
to test your theory then but the
peculiar certainty and Harry seemed
willing to stick its neck out even
further well the letter got here somehow
so I'll just wave it around outside and
call letter for Hogwarts and see if an
owl picks it up dad do you want to come
watch his father shook his head minutely
and kept on reading of course Harry
thought to himself magic was a
disgraceful thing that only stupid
people believed in if his father went so
far as to test the hypothesis or even
watch it being tested
that would be like associating himself
with that only as Harry stumped out the
back door into the backyard did it occur
to him that if an owl did come down and
snatched letter he was going to have
some trouble telling Dad about it but
well that can't really happen can it no
matter what my brain seems to believe if
an owl really comes down and grabs the
envelope I'm going to have worries a lot
more important than what dad thinks
Harry took a deep breath and raised the
envelope into the air he swallowed
calling out letter for Hogwarts while
holding an envelope high in the air in
the middle of your own backyard was
actually pretty embarrassing now that he
thought about it know I'm better than
dad I will use the scientific method
even if it makes me feel stupid letter
Harry said but it actually came out as
more of a whispered croak Harry steal
his will and shouted into the empty sky
letter for Hogwarts can I get an owl
here Harry asked babe amused woman's
voice one of the neighbors
Harry pulled down his hand like he was
on fire and hid the envelope behind his
back like it was drug money his whole
face was hot with shame an old woman's
face peered out from above the
neighboring fence grizzled gray hair
escaping from her hairnet
mrs. fig the occasional babysitter what
are you doing Harry nothing Harry said
in a strangled voice just testing a
really silly
eery did you get your acceptance letter
from Hogwarts Harry frozen place yes
Harry's lips it a little while later I
got a letter from Hogwarts they say they
want my alibi July 31st but but you
don't have an owl port dear I can't
imagine what someone must have been
thinking sending you just the standard
letter a wrinkled arm stretched out over
the fence and open an expectant hand
hardly even thinking at this point Harry
gave over his envelope just leave it to
me dear and in a jiffy or two I'll have
someone over and her face disappeared
from over the fence there was a long
silence in the backyard then a boy's
voice said calmly and quietly what end
chapter 1 thank you to the following
people but tunia Dursley by annie mccabe
miss fig by melissa kessler robert does
reading for dr. Michael there's Evans
this chapters original text production
notes and attribution links along with
archives and much more can be found at
HP mor podcast.com if you would like to
learn more about the art of rationality
please visit les wrong com an online
community of aspiring rationalists
founded by eliezer yudkowsky some sound
effects used are courtesy of the free
sound project the music used is catch
that goblin by Skaven thank you for
listening and come back next week for
chapter 2 everything I believe is false
[Music]