In mountain biking, the act of hopping one’s
bike is called a bunnyhop.
The particular technique shown here is known
is an American bunnyhop, but to me hopping
is hopping.
Learning to hop or learning to hop higher
may be one of your priorities.
It allows you to more easily get over obstacles,
change the orientation of your bike, go higher
on jumps, and most importantly have more fun.
So today we’ll revisit the bunnyhop with
a fresh explanation.
First of all, your bike doesn’t matter much.
Full suspension, full rigid, hardtail, flat
pedals, clipless pedals, they’re all fine.
I’ve done my highest hops on on hardtails
with flat pedals, but as you can see Brian
is doing it clipped in on a full squish.
This is me last summer, bunnyhopping a 60
pound Walmart bike with water in the tires.
So as far as learning goes, any mountain bike
is just fine.
No matter what bike you have, go ahead and
drop your seat as low as it can go.
This will give you more room to maneuver your
bike while learning.
To bunnyhop, you need to jump yourself into
the air and take your bike with you.
You weigh a lot more than your bike, so think
of it as a passenger.
So if you can’t do this, then it’s going
to be even harder while holding your bike.
Make sense?
Now on to the technique.
The first step is to practice getting into
the meerkat position.
That is, standing straight up with your bars
at your waist.
For starters you can just try getting your
front wheel off the ground.
A lot of people have trouble with this part
in particular, and it usually comes down to
the preload.
By this, I mean forcing your weight downwards
before you pop up.
If your bike has suspension it’ll compress,
and you should pop back up in sync with it.
And remember, it’s you that’s popping
up and your bike that’s coming along with
you.
Don’t do this.
Do this.
Once you get the hang of that, you can go
full meerkat by snapping your bars to your
waist.
Okay so preload, meerkat position, what now?
Well, now all you have to do is lunge forwards.
It’s really that simple.
Of course this will only get you so high,
but you now have the tools to go higher.
While going meerkat you should be jumping
straight upwards.
See?
Jump up, snap your bars to your waist, and
continue to jump upwards.
If you do it with enough force, your bike
can come along for the ride.
Don’t worry about your pedals, don’t worry
about what kind of bike you have, just meerkat.
Learning to bunny hop takes practice, and
then you need to learn to time it.
As you approach an obstacle you need to know
when to start pulling up so you won’t case
it.
I recommend practicing with some sticks or
branches to keep the stakes low.
After a while, you’ll get it.
I hope you found this tutorial helpful, or
at least entertaining.
If you still have questions, check the playlist
below for different approaches and explanations
I’ve done.
If you have any bunny hop tips, share them
below so we can all learn.
Thanks for riding with me today and I’ll
see you next time.