Sometimes, YouTube just spreads it's cheeks so wide
It's hard not to grab a bucket of mayonnaise, and go in for a full thrust
And today, I've been given that opportunity
You guys all know about the Ad-pocalypse by now
and in the wake of that there's been a huge string of demonetizations,
of people making way less money,
and overall just a lot of creators and YouTubers losing a lot of their livelihood,
and just getting dinged left and right.
With this piss colored demonetization sign
they show up on your videos, and that's what it feels like.
Pissed.
You got pissed on your soul,
And now you're pissed because most of the time it just doesn't make any sense
and that's fine because all of us YouTubers are dealing with this shit and
You know what, that's just the world we're living in now.
We've all more or less accepted it
But when you see shit like what I'm about to show you, it makes that yellow piss sign a little bit harder to swallow.
That's a golden shower my friends
And we don't all like bathing in piss. Casey Neistat made a video about the Las Vegas shooting
He said, "literally a video about charity where I state all Adsense is going to that charity YouTube says not suitable for advertisers"
"We love what you're doing to help
But no matter the intent our policy is to not run ads on videos about tragedies"
It's their policy, and it doesn't matter what's your intent.
Let's hop on over to Jimmy Kimmel who did, in my opinion have a very powerful monologue on his show
Jimmy Kimmel on the mass shooting in Las Vegas. I'm a huge fan
Jimmy Kimmel and I agree with him actually
But I'm also a big fan of free speech. YouTube if it's your policy to not run ads on videos about
tragedies no matter the intent, then how do you explain this? "Jimmy Kimmel on Mass Shooting in Las Vegas"
GMC ad. Here's an ad for the new Blade Runner movie.
And it's number one on trending! Okay, yesterday IDubbbz made a video
that got 10 million views in the first day
didn't get a blip on trending. So they not only made the conscious decision to put ads on this video in
contradiction of their own statement, they've also decided to trend it number one
This is called selective enforcement. When you have rules that are so general that you can
prosecute pretty much anyone you want, when you use that broadness to enforce a certain ideology, that censorship,
Now as much as I love Jimmy Kimmel and agree with him,
Would YouTube put ads and promote somebody from the,
conflicting side from the right with an opposing view?
I don't think so
I don't at all, and while I disagree with them, like I said
I'm more proponent of free speech and what they're doing is-is clearly picking a side
And they're paying them too. Like ABC needs that Adsense revenue?
ABC Jimmy Kimmel needs that 6 million Adsense revenue? Meanwhile creators are getting pissed on?
literally taking golden showers on the daily? I mean Christ,
I'll take some urine on the face in the heat of the moment, but not on as a daily occurrence
That's too much for me, and-and I assume for most youtubers as well. Even after Philly D tweeted this and it got
350,000 likes, they never responded to the criticism.
In fact, they doubled down. This video has more ads than I have seen in the past month since this ad pocalypse
happened. Just out of curiosity, I went and checked this morning to see if ads were still on the video in
response to Philly D's criticism. Let's have a look, Royal Caribbean, Wells Fargo, University of Phoenix, Geo storm- that movie looks awful
I'm not gonna watch that one. Just to give my opinion.
It's not relevant to this to this video, but seriously this looks like horseshit.
So their response was not only to ignore the criticism, not enforce their own rules,
But to double down and put what seemed like even more ads on the video
And here's the thing I think they should have ads
I think we should all have ads, this whole thing, this outrage is ridiculous
And you know how I know that? I was watching CNN when the shooting was happening. My parents live in Vegas,
They heard about it
They told me, I immediately turned on CNN to see what was going on this was an active, live, shooting
There was a reporter, live on the scene, giving updates. This is a screenshot
I took off my own television. These guys were running ads, 5 minute long ads,
every 5 minutes, when they knew people were watching. Glued to the TV, looking for live updates. This one
I pictured here: 3 out of 7 ads. Here's the ironic touch, that makes you adjust love that golden shower "Brought to you by:
Coca-Cola!
Dr. Pepper!
Pepsi!" You know at first, I was just angry at CNN for
monetizing this tragedy, this live tragedy right? I'm glued to the TV,
I'm looking for updates and these sick fucks are basically just pulling the money lever because that- ratings are so high
But then when I'm think about it after a couple hours. I'm like, hold on a fucking second.
These are the same brands that boycotted YouTube! Coca-Cola,
Dr. Pepper, Pepsi! Dude, these are the same guys that pulled their ads out of YouTube for being
"inappropriate!" That caused these new guidelines that you can't put ads on tragedies unless you're, you know, someone that we approve
like Jimmy Kimmel. Nobody's sincere. These brands don't give a shit about monetizing tragedy. They've been doing it for decades on CNN.
It's just about control and politics and money. That's it.
I saw all these brands that boycotted YouTube, and I'm like oh my god.
So this is confirmed just a total sham. I truly don't think that you'll see any more,
"edgy," interesting, channels coming up in a big way on YouTube anymore. You won't see it.
All you ever gonna see on YouTube anymore is Jake Paul, Logan Paul. You're gonna get more Dude Perfect.
There's no soul left. There's no backbone left.
It's just goo and piss.
And I'll tell you what else, if you want more proof that we are truly living in the darkest timeline; that is Logan Paul.
On a Tonight Show, he preceded Ryan Gosling.
Advertisers are lining up to put their ads on this video.
How is this not trending on all 20 spots? This should be. If I could just get them both dabbing.
I think that we could get number one trending with this video. And with that being said, I've been getting a lot of
steamy yellow piss in my face on a regular basis, that I'm starting to like it. So Hila,
I hope you're hydrated because I'm gonna need you to take a piss on my face. Thanks YouTube for my new fetish. Bye.