Hi!
I'm Vanessa, from SpeakEnglishWithVanessa.com.
Do I speak slowly?
Let's talk about it.
I get a lot of e-mails from students telling
me, "Vanessa, I'm so glad!
I can understand everything you say.
But then I turn on an English TV show, and
I can't understand anything?
Does this mean that you're speaking slowly?"
I wanted to talk about this today because
it's a great question.
I want to make sure that you know exactly
the truth, and find out what's the next step.
First of all, when I'm explaining something,
like today, in these short videos, I want
to make sure that you can understand everything.
So my pronunciation isn't unnatural.
I'm.
Not.
Talking.
Like.
This.
Very.
Slowly.
For.
Children.
I'm not talking like that, but I am talking
clearly, and a little bit reduced.
A little bit slower, because I want to make
sure that you can understand everything.
I'm also talking to a camera.
I know that you are watching, but on my side,
I see a camera, so it's a little bit difficult
to have a natural conversation when someone's
not there.
The reason why I wanted to tell you this,
is because I have a lot of videos on my YouTube
channel with other English-speakers.
There's videos with people through Skype.
There's videos with people in my house, around
my city ... I think this is a really good
way to take your English listening to the
next level.
Start with these videos, more slower explanations,
and then watch videos with my voice ... You
already understand my voice ... plus one other
person.
I'll make sure that in the description and
at the end of this video, I link to some of
those videos so that you can check them out.
Then the next step is to watch a TV show,
or another YouTube video with someone who's
not me.
Someone who you don't completely understand
already.
I think those are good steps, starting with
these explanation videos, then watching a
conversation video that I've had, and then
going to someone else.
That way, you can test your skills and grow
them step-by-step.
Because my goal is to prepare you for the
real world, kind of like a parent who's raising
a child and the goal is to send them out as
an adult and prepare them for the real world,
my goal for you is so that you can understand
anyone, and really communicate in any situation.
Not just with me.
I think that this three-step plan, start with
these basic videos, then go to conversation
videos with me, and then go to conversations
with other people who have a completely different
style of speaking ... That's going to really
help you.
This is something that I integrate into the
course The Fearless Fluency Club.
Each month, we have a conversation with me
and another English-speaker.
Sometimes two other speakers.
That way, you can hear how this natural conversation
sounds.
It's usually pretty fast, but you already
understand my voice, so it's going to help
you to increase step-by-step.
Now, I have a question for you.
I want to know, when you study English, do
you mainly focus on English learning materials,
like this kind of video?
Or do you mainly focus on English TV shows
or movies, some bigger content that's meant
for native speakers?
I think it's good to start with more basic
content, and then move to those more challenging
things, but I want to know for you.
What do you mainly enjoy as you're studying
English?
Let us know in the comments below, and I can't
wait to see what you have to say.
Thanks so much, and I'll see you the next
time.
Bye!
The next step is to download my free e-book,
Five Steps to Becoming a Confident English
Speaker.
I want to help you master English and speak
fluently.
Feel free to subscribe so that you don't miss
new English lessons.
Thanks so much for learning with me.
Bye!