Hi everyone, I’m Vicki and I’m British.
And I’m Jay and I’m American and this
video is long overdue.
Why is it overdue?
I’ve been slow.
A year ago, we made a video about how we both
pronounce 'can' and 'can’t' in English.
It was nearly two years ago.
We say the negative word 'can’t' differently.
She means can’t.
Can’t.
Sometimes when Jay says it, I don’t understand
him.
I don’t want you to see.
I can’t see.
Oh well let me try again.
Why?
I can’t see?
Do you mean you can or you can’t see.
I can’t see.
That video was very popular.
But in the comments a lot of you said you
had a problem.
Yes, a lot of people didn’t want to say
can’t the British way in case they say 'beep'.
Oh, I said a rude word.
Lots of people are worried about that.
They don’t want to sound rude
Some of you told us you say 'cannot' instead.
That’s clear, but it sounds strange.
Cannot is more frequent in written English.
We don’t say it much when we’re speaking.
It sounds stilted.
You don’t want to sound formal and strange.
So what we need to do is work on the vowel
sound – the AH sound.
That way you can say it confidently.
And make sure you don’t get it mixed up
with UH.
This is going to be useful for pronouncing
lots of words, and good for your listening too.
So where should we start?
I think we should look at what’s causing
the problem in the first place.
Too many English vowels.
We have five vowels in the English alphabet,
but we pronounce them in different ways, so
we have lots of vowel sounds.
When I was learning Japanese there were just
five vowel sounds.
It was pretty easy.
Spanish is another language that has five.
If your language has fewer vowel sounds than
English, of course it’s going to be difficult
to hear and say the English ones.
You have to train your ear and learn to move
your mouth muscles differently.
We have twelve pure vowel sounds in English
and we’re going to focus on two that are
very similar.
I thought it was eleven sounds.
Ah.
No.
In American English there are eleven, but
in British English we have twelve.
Really?
Yes, there’s one you don’t say.
What’s that?
o, like in the word lot.
We’ve made another video about that.
But we’re focusing on two other vowel sounds
today: AH and UH.
So you can say can’t and not 'beep'.
Ah I did it again.
So let’s look at these sounds.
AH…
This is the sound I make when Vicki gives
me a foot rub.
AH.
You wish.
And what about UH?
That’s when I’ve made a mistake. UH!
AH.
UH.
AH
is a longer sound.
AH.
And with AH there’s a little more jaw drop.
And you press your tongue down a bit at the
back.
So when your jaw goes down your tongue goes
down too.
And there’s a little tension in your tongue.
Now the other sound, UH.
This is a shorter sound.
Your tongue is completely relaxed.
UH.
And your jaw is a little higher.
Say the sounds with us.
AH.
UH.
Now we need some words to practice.
This is where it gets tricky because sometimes
we use these sounds in different words.
It’s an American and British English difference.
So let’s start with a different vowel sound.
Aaaa.
Here are some words that we both say with
Can, bag, sad, man, fat.
So we both said the vowel sound Aaaa there.
But there are other words where Jay says Aaaa
and I say AH.
Can’t, aunt, past, laugh, class, after.
Did you hear the difference?
I said AH and Jay said Aaaa.
And then there are other words where we both
say AH.
Father, father, llama, llama, calm, calm,
bra, bra.
I think your vowel sound was a little longer
than mine.
Maybe.
We both said AH, but perhaps your AH was a
little shorter than mine?
What do you think?
Let’s try some more.
Dark, dark, barn, barn, march, march, cart,
cart.
Our vowel sounds were the same again but our
R sounds were different.
Yeah.
I’m from just north of London in England,
and we don’t pronounce our Rs in these words.
There are parts of the UK where people do,
but most people don’t.
We’ve made another video about that.
OK.
Now there’s another group of words where
you say AH, but I don’t.
Doll, doll, fond, fond, lock, lock, hot, hot,
gosh, gosh.
Did you hear the difference?
I said AH – gosh.
But you didn’t.
No, I used the other extra vowel sound that
we have in British English.
The twelfth vowel sound.
It sounds so British!
It’s just what we say.
But let’s recap so far.
There are some words where I say AH and Jay
doesn’t, and some words where we both say
it, and some where Jay says it and I don’t.
OK.
But what about the other important sound.
We need to look at UH.
Yes.
UH is more straightforward because we both
say this sound in much the same words.
Cup, cup, hut, hut, luck, luck, love, love,
come, come, dull, dull.
So UH is a shorter sound and you need to keep
your tongue relaxed.
Let’s compare UH with AH now.
See if you can hear the difference.
Cart cut, carp cup, dark duck, barn bun, calm
come.
Hot hut, lock luck, cot cut, fond fund, doll
dull.
If you find it hard, you’re not alone.
Yes, it’s tricky.
It’s about small movements of the tongue
and the jaw.
It just takes practice, but you’ll get it. Now,
do we have any sentences?
Yes.
I’ve got one for you to say and one for
me to say and you can try saying them with
us.
Your one has UH sounds.
OK.
'Don’t be unhappy, love.
Come to lunch with me and let’s have fun!'
OK, my one has AH sounds.
'I can’t meet you after class because I’ll
be in the bath.'
You mean the bath.
And that’s it for today everyone.
If you’ve enjoyed this video please give
it a like and share it with a friend.
See you all next Friday.
Bye
Bye-bye.