- Teaching for English language learners
is good teaching for everybody.
- It is definitely about building their
literacy skills but also their confidence.
I have a range of students from beginners
to high intermediate students.
So I use the inductive strategy
because it can meet the needs of everyone.
Yes, making connections because
she said the word, remember.
This makes me remember.
- The goal is to make the lesson
accessible to all students.
Wanna see my picture?
(cross-talking)
You do like or you don't like my picture?
- [Student] I don't like.
- Aw, that makes me feel sad.
Background knowledge is not just
what students bring to the class,
what they've learned previously.
It's also providing students
with the information
they need to be able to
access an upcoming lesson.
Also, the students in my class
actually speak three or more languages.
Okay, English just doesn't happen
to be one of them yet,
so they're learning.
Write it, yeah, in your lan--
in Pashto or in Farsi.
- Fair is not equal, you know.
And it's true, if with
differentiation too.
I mean, not everybody will
get the same exact text
or use the same strategy, but it's fair
because you're meeting every
student where they are,
and we're helping them
progress to the next level.
Okay.
- [Student] We don't like it.
- Sometimes I pair students
by same proficiency.
Other times I might choose
a more difficult text
but pair my beginners with a
higher proficiency student.
- [Student] Red tile, middle
school the worst years.
- An easy way to differentiate is
to have put videos at slower speeds.
It's not just a list of strategies that
comes out of within
relationships of students.
When I was first starting
Spanish, I was very scared.
Being a environment where
students are going to risk.
Where people are gonna
have a sense of humor.
There's 2/3, it's two, four.
I teach English, not math, two, four.
- I think of differentiation more
like a mindset, than on
Tuesday I differentiate.
You're constantly thinking how do I
make this accessible to everyone?
All right, last step.