I realize I'm a little bit late on this one,
Me and Hila just returned from a little vacation for our four year anniversary.
Pound it.
We had a great time, thank you.
Let me explain;
Casey Neistat is a very popular YouTuber
who made a video a couple days ago
Casey: Hillary Clinton.
I will be voting
for Hillary Clinton.
Ethan: Casey endorsed Hillary with such
with such gusto, he basically fucked her in the ass.
And gave her a reach-around.
I mean he went
full service for her.
Which is fine.
And fra--frankly, I even respect it
a little bit, because I know it can be so divisive and difficult
to talk about politics.
So it's cool that he did that
and I respect that. But!
Towards the end of the video,
he gets into this whole thing about how
We're all mora--morally obligated
to vote for Hillary
and he even goes
as far as to
telling people to ask their favorite
creators on YouTube
to "get a spine,"
and "backbone,"
and make sure that we all vote...
for Hillary.
Casey: I want to end this by calling out all the big YouTubers.
Some I know, and some you viewers might know.
See, making videos like this... they're not popular,
they're not gonna get you subscribers,
they're not gonna boost your view counts.
But there is something much more valuable than subscribers or dollars --
And that's backbone.
Ethan: That kinda rubbed me the wrong way.
Before I do get into this, I just wanna say that
Casey is a wonderful guy.
He makes great videos, and he's one of the truly creative people on YouTube,
And I have nothing but admiration for him.
I can disagree with Casey without hating him.
And that's kinda the center of what I'm talking about here,
is that... we need to be able to discuss things without everybody losing their fucking mind,
and hating each other.
Now the way Casey talks about Donald Trump,
is that he--he almost implies that he's some kind of Adolf Hitler.
Casey: This is about a megalomaniac
who's driven by nothing but ego.
A man who cares exactly zero about the people of this country.
And if this guy gets elected,
and you stood back with your arms folded
and didn't speak out against him,
it makes you complicit [complacent].
It makes you partially responsible for handing him the reigns of power.
Ethan: And implies that if you don't vote for Hillary,
you're gonna be liable for whatever holocaust
he has up his sleeve.
And the way he talks about him,
he almost paints him as an inhuman demon,
okay?
Which is just so unproductive.
Hillary supporters think Donald is the Devil,
Hillary: You could put
half of Trump supporters into what
I call the "Basket of Deplorables."
The racist, sexist, homophobic,
xenophobic, Islamophobic - you name it.
Ethan: And Donald thinks that Hillary's the Devil.
Donald: ...but he made a deal with the Devil - she's the Devil.
...to see him sign on with the devil.
Ethan: They all perpetuate this notion.
And now, it's so confusing I don't understand
what to believe anymore.
If you put on CNN, Donald Trump is now a rapist, apparently,
with like a small gymnasium of women whose,
fuckin', pussies he's grabbed.
Donald, old recording: Grab 'em by the pussy.
Ethan: Hillary Clinton is married to a serial rapist,
you know,
i--it's... they're so - it's like,
"Why are we talking about how people are rapists?"
I mean these are just allegations, I don't know
if these people are rapists or not, but it's like...
Nobody is even talking about any real issues.
Everybody's just accusing each other of
actually being a rapist.
Like, has this gone too far?
Like, Trump shows up to the debate, the debates,
with like a small gymnasium of people
who Bill Clinton has apparently raped.
Maybe next year during the debates, half the people
could be Bill Clinton's rape victims,
and the other half Trump rape victims.
I just want all rape victims at next year's debates please.
No normal people at all.
Casey: So if your favorite YouTuber says things like,
"I don't like to talk politics on my channel," or
"I'm not going to reveal who I'm voting for,"
call them out.
Ethan: I think kinda the opposite of what he's saying.
Don't fucking listen to me.
Don't listen to Casey. We're just -- I'm just a YouTuber.
How does that qualify me to tell you who to vote for,
who to fucking elect as  President?
I literally go to the grocery store with two-hundred shirts on
and you're looking to me for advice on who to vote for President?
There have got to be better people out here to advise you on that.
And here's the worst part: if you're someone who
generally is like, "Yeah, I don't like either of them,
neither of them really represent who I am as a person,
and I don't like either of them,"
if you're like, "I'm not gonna vote for them."
Each side says to you,
"Oh, well you're a f-- you not voting is basically
voting for my - for the other guy."
Or, "You not voting is basically voting for the other guy."
And here's Casey himself saying, "If you don't vote for Hillary,
you're responsible for the Holocaust, part two."
It's like, tone it down, dawg! Get off your fucking white horse.
You just make fucking vlogs!
You just fly drones around New York City!
Let's all tone it fucking down.
The climate is so toxic right now on both sides, that
you can't even be in the middle, because they'll call -- they'll yell at you and tell you,
you are the Devil for not choosing one of 'em.
And God forbid you try to choose a third-party guy.
A vote for the third-party guy,
which is basically a vote against the system,
you ask one of them, "That's a vote for Hillary!"
"That's a vote for Trump!"
In short, guys, don't let people bully you
into voting one way or the other with their extreme, hateful shit.
It's not fair that you get guilted and shamed into voting one way or another,
and it's really fucked up that you get ostracized for
being in the middle.
For trying to be a sane, rational person, who's like
"Well, I haven't made up my mind, they're both kinda
insane, I don't, like..." You're the Devil now.
Don't let people bully you and make you feel like shit because you want to be in the middle.
More people should be in the middle.
Most people should be in the middle.
But it's like this.
There's not two teams, we're all American.
And don't let people tell you that voting for a third party is a wasted vote -
because voting for a third party is a vote against the system itself.
We need more options,
okay,
it's just not enough.
Everyone just needs to fucking chill out, and have a sodie pop.
So, in short, who am I voting for?
Only one option.
Hugh Mungus for President. *Patriotic music*
Angry Woman: Hugh Mungus what?
Hugh Mungus: Hugh Mungus.
So I urge everybody now following me who believes in me
write in "Hugh Mungus" for President of the United States, 2016
Angry Woman: Is that sexual harassment?
Hugh Mungus: No, it's Hugh Mungus.
Ethan: Make Hugh Mungus great again.
God bless America
*Chair falling* *Ethan Klein's cough™ - grunt*
We're all so fucked, dude.
We are all so fucked.